Guide to the Dan Nimrod papers, 1938-2002 MS2192
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Correspondence - Canada, 1977-2002; MS2192 Series 2; 3 Linear feet
  - Common Ground (Axbelbaum, Sender), 06/23/1992-07/13/1992 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Concordia University, 04/28/1982-12/19/1994 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Conflict Quarterly, 08/04/1977-09/29/1989 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Congregations, 1977-1998 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    [from contents page in folder:] Beth Israel Congregation; Beth Zion Congregation; Chevra Thilim Pinsker Kinyan Torah; Moncton Congregation; Shaar Hashomayim; Shaare Zedek Congregation; Temple Emanu-el, Westmount; Young Israel of Chomedy
  - Conseil de la Presse du Quebec, 02/06/1995-04/29/1997 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Consulate of Germany, 09/25/1991-04/13/1992 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Consulate of Israel 1980-1984, 10/05/1979-07/16/1984 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Consulate of Israel 1985-2000, 04/25/1985-12/28/2000 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Consulate of South Africa, 02/10/1985-02/10/1994 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Consulate General of the United States, 11/19/1983 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Cotler, Irwin (prof), 04/26/1979-12/30/1982 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Cummings, Jack L., 11/28/1980-12/14/1981 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Dermer, Ruth, 06/25/1984-06/11/2000 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Ehrenworth, Rose, 12/03/1979-09/14/1994 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Embassy of Germany, 01/20/1992-01/06/1993 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Embassy of Israel, 08/23/1990-07/31/1992 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Embassy of the United States, 11/21/1983-02/27/1984 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Fackenheim, Emile L. (rabbi), 10/01/1978-11/26/1978 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Fernandez, Marisa, 09/15/1998-10/01/1998 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Fisher, B.K. (dr), 01/10/1985-09/13/1990 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Frankel, Jack L., 02/23/1996-08/22/2000 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Friends of Ariel - Wolman, Leonard, 06/02/1992-02/23/1995 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Friends of South Africa, 03/28/1988-01/30/1990 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Gazette, the, 09/02/1977-08/28/2000 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Gazette, the - Ombundsman, 06/07/1981-10/21/1991 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Globe & Mail, the, 08/09/1977-08/28/2000 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Government of Canada, 01/25/1980-11/15/1995 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Haccoun, Robert (dr), 09/07/1984-10/31/1984 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Hecht, T.O., 03/20/1979-04/12/2001 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Herut-Hatzohar - Zionist Revisionists, 06/18/1978-08/17/1987 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Hoffman, G. (dr) - Vanier College, 10/30/1978-09/24/1981 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Hollinger Inc., 01/05/1989-04/27/2000 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Horn, Isidor [Yitzhak], 11/02/1981-12/30/1982 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Horowitz, Aaron (dr), 03/19/1980-09/15/1983 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Human Rights Institute of Canada - Ritchie, Marguerite (dr.), 09/28/2001-04/02/2002 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - International Federation of Body Builders - Weider, Ben 1981-1997, 04/10/1981-12/15/1997 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - International Federation of Body Builders - Ben Weider 1998, 01/05/1998-12/10/1998 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - International Federation of Body Builders - Ben Weider 1999-2002, 01/18/1999-01/23/2002 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Israel visiting academics, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    [from contents page of folder:] Claude Gandelman, Ph.D.; Joseph Ginat, Ph.D.; Matitiahu Maysel, Ph.D.; Joseph Nevo, Ph.D.; Haim Shaked, Ph.D.; (Dr.) Simcha B. Werner, Ph.D.; Miscellaneous Documents
  - Jacobson, Samuel, 10/23/1977-05/22/1984 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Jewish Action Initiative, 05/22/1992-08/30/1993 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Jewish National Fund of Canada (J.N.F.), 12/07/1981-03/24/1994 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Jewish Western Bulletin, 12/21/1981-02/18/1992 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - John Coutts Library Services Ltd. 1998-2002, 06/12/1998-02/15/2002 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Jordan is Arab Palestine (J.I.P.), 01/29/1982-08/16/1984 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Kahn, Leon, 12/29/1994-09/11/2000 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Kinberg, A., 07/31/1980-12/28/1983 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Kirk, David (prof), 05/18/1992-09/11/2000 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Kuperstock, Nathan (dr.), 11/20/1981-07/28/2000 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Kussner, Mr. & Mrs. M., 11/16/1980-11/18/1981 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Landis, Herbert, 07/30/1999-01/01/2000 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Levenson, Harvey, 08/14/1985-02/25/1992 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Lewis, Yakov, 12/17/1987-11/23/1988 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Margo, Peter, 11/22/1980-08/25/1998 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - McGill University - Troy, Gil (prof.), 03/31/1982-06/19/2000 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Magen David Campaign (M.D.A.) Jan-Sept 1978, 01/07/1978-09/11/1978 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Magen David Campaign (M.D.A.) Oct 1978, 10/06/1978-10/31/1978 (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Magen David Campaign (M.D.A.) Nov-Dec 1978, 11/02/1978-12/31/1978 (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - Magen David Campaign (M.D.A.) Jan-Feb 1979, 01/08/1979-02/27/1979 (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - Magen David Campaign (M.D.A.) Mar 1979-Jun 1980, 03/01/1979-06/27/1980 (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Magen David Campaign (M.D.A.) A-F, 06/01/1978-04/11/1979 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Magen David Campaign (M.D.A.) G-H, 10/12/1978-01/12/1979 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Magen David Campaign (M.D.A.) I-J, 10/13/1978-06/12/1980 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Magen David Campaign (M.D.A.) K-O, 12/18/1978-07/05/1979 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Magen David Campaign (M.D.A.) P, 07/12/1978-06/27/1980 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Media-General, 1977-2000 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    [from contents page in folder:] Actualite - Lisee, Jean-Francois; Bulletin, The; Canada Courier; C.J.A.D.; Concordia Thursday Report; Hillel Star, the; Hour, the; Le Journal, Le Soleil; Macleans; Mirror, the; Montreal Star, the; National Post, the; News & Chronicle, the; Ottawa Citizen, the; Ottawa Journal, the; Saturday Night; Sunshine News
  - Media - Jewish, 1978-2001 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    [from contents page in folder:] Canadian Zionist; Images; Jewish Post, the; Jewish Standard, the; Jewish Times, the; Jewish Tribune, the; Jews for Judaism; Leader Post, the; Ottawa Jewish Bulletin & Review, the; Viewpoints
  - Network Canada, 10/17/1984-04/07/1989 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Neufeld, Franceen, 11/10/1989-02/20/1996 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Organizations, 1978-2000 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    [from contents page in folder:] Association for the welfare of soldiers in Israel; Board of Jewish Education; Canada-Israel Chamber of Commerce; Conservative Sisterhood Canada; Hadassah-Wizo Organization of Canada; Jewish Community Research Institute; Mizrachi Partners in Torat Yisrael; NOAM Jewish Centre; Toronto Jewish Cultural Council
  - Our Canada, 05/27/1980-07/19/1984 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Owens, Hugh, 11/22/1996-06/26/1997 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Pollack, Aaron, 03/15/1982-04/10/1985 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Pollard, Jonathan - Citizens for Justice for Elaine Zeitz Pollard, 10/16/1994-01/13/1995 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Poray-Wybranowski, Anna, 06/06/1985-12/14/1986 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Poupko, Reuben (rabbi), 08/23/1989-01/1996 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Prime Minister's Office, 11/19/1983-02/07/1997 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Rosen, Leonard, 12/03/1978-12/16/1981 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Samuel & Saidye Bronfman Family Foundation - Swan, Peter (dr.), 02/19/1982-05/10/1982 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Save All Jews Everywhere (S.A.J.E.), 07/11/1994 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Schwartz, G. & G. (dr), 09/1977-09/30/1986 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Shainhouse, Sam, 11/07/1984-11/1987 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Simon Wiesenthal Centre for Holocaust Studies (Friends of) (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Special Interest A-L, 1977-2002 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    [from contents page in folder:] Adler, Joseph; Airst, Mr.; Airst, Lisa; Avrich, Dina; Azimov, Sheldon; Batshaw, M.; Bellow, Saul; Ben-Dor, Gabriel (prof); Berman, Ralph; Berzon, Chananya (rabbi); Bick, Walter; Black, Manny & Marcie; Blodgett, Gunnar; Canadian Friends of the International Christ; Carmel, Israel; Centoni, Maria; Centre de Reproduction Copie Rox Inc.; Cohen, Iris & George; Cohen, Montague; Comeau, Jacques; Corber, Rudy; Chernack, Michael; Egri, George; Elbaz, Henri; Elzas, N.; Faiman, Rhona; Feinstein, Morris; Fisher; Friedman, A.; Garfinkle, M.; Gelber, Sadie; Glazer, Sidney; Goldberg, Gershon; Goldstein, Y.; Goody, Max; Gordon, Saul; Granovsky, Phil; Greben, Stanley (dr); Greenway, Ellen; Greenberg, Esther; Guttman, Gerald; Guttman, Joseph; Haberman, Y.; Hadassah-WIZO Organization of Canada (Smiley, Ellen); Hahn, Richard; Halpern, Esther (dr); Hazan, Bobby; Herrmann, Klaus (dr); Hoffman, Ann; Howlet, F.; Hurwitz, Hillel; International Jewish Correspondence; Jacobson, Samuel; Jewish War Veterans of Canada; Kahanoff Foundation; Keeler, Judy; Klein, Esther; Kuban, B.; Landau, Hermann; Lealand, James; Lequire, Steve; Leslie, Rose; Liebman, Howard; Levy, Shlomo; Lewin, Chaim; Lieberman, Brett; Leiblein, Sam; Lightstone, Jack (prof.); Logan, James C.; Lustman, Francois
  - Special Interest M-Z, 1977-2002 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    [from contents page of folder:] Malamet, C.K.; Malus, Natalie & Eli; Mandelbaum, Isaac; Marder, Aaron; Mayer, Louise; Miller, Ezra R.; Milner, Ben C.; Moidell, Sid; Mueller, H.; Nehorai, M. (prof); Na'amat Canada; Naguib, Selim; Plaut, Gunther (rabbi); Polotsky, Paul; Rapaport, Yehuda; Reitman, D.; Reitman, Howard; Rheaume, Gilles; Recht, Hershel S.; Robinson, Ira; Rosen, Dolores; Sambatyon, Moshe; Schindler, N.R.; Scott, Eric; Seligson, Lou; Serfaty, S.; Shapiro, Harry; Sher, Carol; Shmidman, Joshua (rabbi); Silver, Louis; Simon & Shuster, Inc.; Singer, Clifford; Sochaczevsky, Amos; Sokoloff, Sam; Solman, M.; Stein, Syd; Steinberg, H.; Steinmetz, Oren (dr); Stern, B.; Stern, Harry (rabbi & dr.); Stern, M.S.; Stermer, Sam; Sugarman, Ben; Tansey, Beve; Theall, Margaret; Thomson, Dale; Tiltin, Ivor; Tobiasz, Zvi; Tucker, Lois; Uten, Nissen; Vanier College; V.G.; Vermete, Cecile; Vernon, Frank; Vineberg, Philip (Q.C.); Webber, Harvey; Weistein, Meir; Wolfe, Sharon; Wolle, Harry; Wolman, Leonard M.; Zbik, Wladyslaw Alfred; Zimmerman, Rubin
  - Suburban 1977-1992, 10/11/1977-10/14/1992 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Suburban 1993-2000, 01/26/1993-08/28/2000 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Tehiya Canada - Grief, Howard (President), 04/07/1980-03/07/1989 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Toronto Star, 08/08/1977-08/28/2000 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Toronto Zionist Council - Smolack, Helen (director) 1981-1991, 11/11/1981-11/13/1991 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Toronto Zionist Council 1992-1996, 01/29/1992-12/26/1996 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Toronto Zionist Council 1997-1998, 09/04/1997-12/30/1998 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Toronto Zionist Council 1999-2002, 01/18/1999-04/18/2002 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Toronto Zionist Council - Misc. Documents, 1986-1995 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - United Church, 06/23/1993-07/08/1993 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - University of Toronto Library, 03/08/1979-03/28/1979 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Vrba, Rudolph (dr), 11/10/1980-05/13/1981 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Vineberg, Stephen A., 11/11/1977-02/16/2001 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Weiner, Gerry (Hon), 09/07/1984-05/11/2000 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Weisz, Zoltan, 11/17/1978-09/07/1981 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Zimmerman, Rubin, 10/01/1981-03/24/1985 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Letters to the Editor, 1979-08/28/2000 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Open Letters by D. Nimrod, 07/09/1980-08/18/1999 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - "Dear Friends" letters, 05/11/1981-03/31/2000 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - "Dear Reader" letters, 1980-04/17/1991 (Box 4, Folder 45)
- Correspondence - Germany, 1979-2002; MS2192 Series 3; 1.5 Linear feet
  This series contains Nimrod's correspondence with people and organizations in Germany. The material dates from 1979-2002. The majority of the writings are Nimrod's correspondence with Erich Sontag, a commentator with similar views to those of Nimrod. These folders also contain Sontag's writings that he sent to Nimrod. This series is organized by correspondent's last name or organization name, then chronologically within each folder. The folder labeled "Special Interest" contains multiple correspondents, sorted alphabetically within that folder.
  - International Christian Embassy - Jerusalem, 07/14/1994 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Komm-mit Magazine, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Sontag, Erich A. 1983-1985, 01/22/1983-01/08/1986 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Sontag, Erich A. 1986, 01/02/1986-12/15/1986 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Sontag, Erich A. 1987-1988, 01/15/1987-10/15/1988 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Sontag, Erich A. 1989-1990, 04/01/1989-12/30/1990 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Sontag, Erich A. 1991-1992, 01/08/1991-12/18/1992 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Sontag, Erich A. 1993-1994, 01/07/1993-12/20/1994 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Sontag, Erich A. 1995, 01/18/1995-11/26/1995 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Sontag, Erich A. 1996-1997, 01/05/1996-12/13/1997 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Sontag, Erich A. 1998, 04/15/1998-11/12/1998 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Sontag, Erich A. 1999, 02/21/1999-09/1999 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Sontag, Erich A. 2000-2002, 04/05/2000-04/02/2002 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Special Interest, 1979-2000 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    [from contents page of folder:] Embassy of Israel; International Books in Print; Juristenzeitung; Meyer, Hartmut; Osteuropa; Rohler, Andreas; Springer, Axel; Ticauer, Sholomo (prof); Troy State University Europe
- Correspondence - United Kingdom, 1977-2002; MS2192 Series 4; 1.5 Linear feet
  This series contains Nimrod's correspondence with people and organizations in the United Kingdom. The material dates from 1977-2002. Sidney Goodman, a Zionist activist, is the most prominent correspondent in this series. These folders also contain Goodman's writings that he sent to Nimrod. This series is organized by correspondent's last name or organization name, then chronologically within each folder. Folders labeled "Special Interest," "Media-Jewish," "Archives - Libraries - Research Institutes - Misc.," and "Organizations" contain multiple correspondents, sorted alphabetically within those folders.
  - Archives/Libraries/Research Institutes, 04/03/1980 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Betar/Tagar - The Promised Land - King, Alexander, 01/11/1992-01/19/1994 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Binaisa, Godfrey, 06/27/1984-07/03/1984 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Brawn [Braun], Maureen, 12/10/1982-01/11/1983 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    on label, name is misspelled: should be Braun, not Brawn
  - B.I.P.A.C. (Britain & Israel) - Prettie, Terrence (Hon), 02/18/1979-06/02/1992 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Centre for the study of Judaism and Jewish/Christian Relations - Brearley, Margaret, 02/26/1986-08/24/1990 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Christian Organizations - Christian Friends of Israel - White, Derek, 02/23/1982-12/22/1998 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Christian Organizations - Prayer for Israel, 01/04/1982-09/22/1986 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Conservative Friends for Israel - Fiddler, Michael, 07/20/1982-09/24/1986 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Davies, Jack, 05/29/1978-03/24/1981 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Edwards, R.K. (dr), 08/21/1978-12/10/1980 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Feld, Jesse Z., 03/09/1990-10/26/1990 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Gilbert, Martin John, 08/08/1978-02/20/1979 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Goodman, Sidney 1978-1981, 07/19/1978-12/31/1981 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Goodman, Sidney 1982-1983, 07/01/1982-12/16/1983 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Goodman, Sidney 1984-1986, 01/18/1984-12/22/1986 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Goodman, Sidney 1987-1990, 01/04/1987-12/06/1990 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Goodman, Sidney 1991-1992, 01/30/1991-12/28/1992 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Goodman, Sidney 1993-1996, 01/19/1993-12/05/1996 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Goodman, Sidney 1997-1998, 01/24/1997-12/22/1998 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Goodman, Sidney 1999, 01/08/1999-12/28/1999 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Goodman, Sidney 2000-2002, 01/14/2000-03/11/2002 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Goodman, Sidney - Miscellaneous Documents, 04/14/1980-07/28/1995 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Graus, Eric (Pres) - Likud-Herut UK, 08/18/1986-03/08/2001 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Hertz, Elan, 01/19/1994-06/18/1994 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Herut-Hatzohar - Likud Zionist Revisionist, 11/08/1978-10/03/2000 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Institute for the Study of Terrorism - Becker, Jillian, 03/18/1988-07/20/1988 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Israel Bulletin - Barder, Christopher - Pro-Israel Hasbarah, 11/28/1993-03/09/2001 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Jackson, Leslie 1978-1979, 05/03/1978-12/28/1979 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Jackson, Leslie 1980-1991, 02/29/1980-12/07/1991 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Jakobovits, Immanuel (chief rabbi), 03/31/1981-12/31/1981 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - J.I.P. (Jordan is Arab Palestine) - Silver, Mia, 08/06/1978-07/18/1997 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Kline, Irv, 05/10/1994-08/20/1995 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Leci, Colin L. (dr), 04/05/1994-10/04/2000 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Media - Jewish, 1978-2000 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    [from contents page of folder:] Jewish Chronicle, London; Jewish Herald, London; Jewish Observer, London; Zionist Standard, London
  - MEMO - Laffin, John (dr), 05/02/1984-1989 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Mid East Mirror, 04/15/1992-07/02/1993 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Morris, Conrad, 01/16/1996-08/18/2000 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Organizations, 1977-1985 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    [from contents page of folder:] B'nai B'rith Hillel House; Impact International; Joint Israel Appeal; Zionist Federation
  - Rakusen, Michael, 01/18/1980-11/06/2001 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Rose, J., 07/18/1979-04/01/1982 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Rubin, Stanley, 01/18/1980-01/05/1986 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Salasnik, Rafi, 09/18/1981-12/02/1982 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Soviet Labour Review, 01/12/1984-01/22/1984 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Special Interest, 1978-1997 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    [from contents page of folder:] Abrahams, B.Z. (mrs); Bethell, Nicholas (Lord); Bloch, Lionel; Caplan, Steven; Chachami, Ilan; Cockerel, H.; Fish, Isidore; Fisher, David; Glyn, Stuart; Goldsmith; Goulden, Mark; Hoffman, Paul (esq); Hyman; Lax, Julian; Oberman, Barbara; Schalit, L.; Stamler, Robin; Syndic Oil (Rothschild, Lord); Willers, Ruth; Zionist Year Book - Barwell, Beatrice
  - Stein, Cyril, 04/28/1979-03/16/1982 (Box 5, Folder 46)
- Correspondence - United States, 1956-2002; MS2192 Series 5; 10.5 Linear feet
  This series contains Nimrod's correspondence with people and organizations in the United States. The material dates from 1956-2002. Some more prominent correspondents include Monroe Spen, a Sarasota, Florida, real estate developer who founded Friends of the Jerusalem Temple Mount Inc., and Leonard Horwin, a former U.S. diplomat and mayor of Beverly Hills, California. Horwin self-published a newsletter called Plain Talk, copies of which Nimrod collected and included in his files of correspondence with Horwin. This series is organized by correspondent's last name or organization name, then chronologically within each folder. Folders labeled "Special Interest," "Media-Jewish," "Archives - Libraries - Misc.," and "Organizations" contain multiple correspondents, sorted alphabetically within those folders.
  - Aaron, R. (dr) 1981-1986, 02/09/1981-12/12/1986 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Aaron, R. 1987-1998, 04/22/1987-01/30/1998 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Adelson, Howard (prof), 10/12/1979-07/26/1985 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Ahavat Ysrael Synagogue - Silver Spring Jewish Center - Kranz, Herzel (rabbi), 02/01/1981-08/27/1982 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Alexander, Edward (prof U. of Washington), 05/06/1979-02/26/2001 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Alpert, Buzz, 01/08/1980-03/10/1983 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Alster, Joe, 04/08/1997-05/08/2000 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - American Friends of Hall of Heroism - Singer, Eugene, 05/08/1979-03/08/1982 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - American Friends of Israel Community Development Foundation - Liben, Barry (pres), 07/27/1994-09/11/1994 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - American Historical Review, 07/1985-09/10/1985 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - American Israel Political Control Association (AIPCA) - Pro-Arab Organization, 08/12/1991 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - American Israel Public Affairs Committee (A.I.P.A.C.) - Pro-Israel Organization, 03/1981-10/04/1990 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - American Jewish Alternatives to Zionism, 04/13/1994 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - American Jewish Archives, 02/23/1979-07/16/1980 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - American Historical Society, 10/25/1977-06/11/1985 (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - American Jewish Yearbook, 07/1987-11/15/2000 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Americans for a Safe Israel (AFSI), 12/22/1978-12/17/1986 (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Americans for a Safe Israel (A.F.S.I.) 1987-1996, 01/26/1987-12/05/1996 (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Americans for a Safe Israel (A.F.S.I.) 2000-2001, 04/26/2000-04/16/2001 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Americans for a Safe Israel (A.F.S.I.) - Misc. Documents 1979-1982, 01/26/1979-12/1982 (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - Americans for a Safe Israel (A.F.S.I.) - Misc. Documents 1983-1984, 02/1983-11/1984 (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - Americans for a Safe Israel (A.F.S.I.) - Misc. Documents 1985-1986, 01/1985-12/17/1986 (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - Americans for a Safe Israel (A.F.S.I.) - Misc. Documents 1987-1988, 07/09/1987-04/01/1988 (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - Americans for a Safe Israel (A.F.S.I) - Misc. Documents 1989 (Box 5, Folder 70)
  - Americans for undivided Israel - Topas, George, 02/18/1979-06/30/2000 (Box 5, Folder 71)
  - Anne Frank Institute of Philadelpha - "Lest We Forget" - Littell, Franklin (dr), 09/21/1981-12/20/1997 (Box 5, Folder 72)
  - Ann Frank Institute of Philadelpha - "Lest We Forget" - Littel, Franklin (dr) - Selected articles, 03/1981-1991 (Box 5, Folder 73)
  - Anti-Defamation League of B'nai B'rith (A.D.L.), 05/15/1978-08/28/2000 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Antin-Untermeyer, Ester, 12/19/1978-09/29/1982 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Archives - Libraries - Misc., 1978-1999 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    [from contents page of folder:] Army Library; Association for Jewish Studies; The New York Public Library; Serial Records Division (Harvard College)
  - Arnovitz, Benton M., 07/09/1993-09/27/1993 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Auerbach, Jerold (prof Wellsley College), 09/10/1993-11/19/1993 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Baldwin, Sidney (prof) - The Joshua Circle, 09/12/1984-01/26/1990 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Barsel, Uriah, 03/09/1996-08/14/1997 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Bell, J. Bowyer (dr Columbia University), 09/28/1977-04/25/1978 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Belton, Albert B. (dr), 01/01/1981-05/06/1981 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Ben Ami, Y. 1979-1981, 06/26/1979-12/08/1981 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Ben Ami, Y. 1982-1985, 01/07/1982-12/29/1987 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Ben Gali, Simcha, 12/21/1978-01/30/1981 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Ben Moshe, Shmuel, 01/20/1978-12/17/1980 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Beres, Louis-Rene (prof Purdue University), 12/08/1998-04/26/2000 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Berman, Collette, 03/21/1996-03/26/2002 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Betar-Tagar [New York], 05/30/1978-06/02/1992 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    folder also includes Milwaukee Betar
  - Bible Light - Josephson, Elmer, 03/16/1981-01/30/1997 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - B'nai B'rith Hillel Foundation - Hasten, Renee, 04/20/1979-07/27/1984 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - B'nai B'rith Women, 12/15/1983-07/08/1984 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Bornstein, H.Z., 12/10/1998-01/12/2001 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Brandes, Joseph (dr & prof), 02/19/1979-04/10/1979 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Brodsky, Bernard, 02/20/1989-12/24/1997 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Brotherhood to Prevent Genocide - Jewish Identity Centre/Operation Truth - Riz, Jaacov, 05/16/1978-10/19/1984 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Brotherhood to Prevent Genocide - Jewish Identity Centre/Operation Truth - Riz, Jaacov - Misc. Documents, 01/09/1983-12/27/1984 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Burt, Robert (prof - Yale school of law), 07/25/1994-08/05/1994 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - CAUSA International, 06/22/1984-08/25/1985 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Centre for Global Security Inc. - Pritikin, Roland (Brig Gen) 1974-1986, 12/06/1974-12/12/1986 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Centre for Global Security Inc. - Pritikin, Roland (Brig Gen) 1987-1991, 01/08/1987-04/06/1990 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Centre for Global Security Inc. - Pritikin, Roland (Brig Gen), 02/12/1992-08/19/1996 (Box 6, Folder 29)